Guide to the Augustus Taber Murray Papers SC0221
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Augustus Taber Murray papers
1900-1940
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Murray, Augustus Taber
SC0221
1.25 Linear Feet
Contents include manuscript lectures and sermons, notes and newsclippings about Professor Murray, and correspondence with Herbert Hoover regarding Murray's Service as Head of the Quaker congregation in Washington, D.C. during Hoover's administration.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Mrs. Thomas Moss, 1979.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of classical literature at Stanford (1892-1932; emeritus, 1932-1940) and member of the Society of Friends.
Description of the Collection
Contents include manuscript lectures and sermons, notes and newsclippings about Professor Murray, and correspondence with Herbert Hoover regarding Murray's Service as Head of the Quaker congregation in Washington, D.C. during Hoover's administration.
College teachers.; Lectures.; Speeches.; Sermons.; Quakers.; Hoover, Herbert; Stanford University. Department of Classics; Murray, Augustus Taber; Hoover, Lou Henry, 1874-1944; Murray, Augustus Taber; Marvin, Lloyd H.
- Biographical Information
  - Biography (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Information for National Cyclopedia of American Biography (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Excerpt Pan-Pacific Who's Who (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tribute --March 11, 1940 --Memorial Church, Dr. D. C. Gardner (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Resolution --Academic Council, Stanford University, April 5, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Paper --conferring degree of Doctor of Laws (Haverford College) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Excerpt --Irish Monthly, January 1915, concerning Murray's translation of the Odyssey (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Excerpt from "Autobiography" by John Cowper Powys, 1934, concerning Murray's translation of the Illiad and the Odyssey (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Hall, Mildred (Pres. Hoover's Secretary) 3/1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hendee, Hunter 10/8/35 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hoover, Herbert 1/9/29, 4/23/30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hoover, Lou Henry undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Marvin, Lloyd H. 10/7/29, 10/9/29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing
    - 3/21/23, Dr. Edward Capps (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 2/17/31, Editor of the American Friend (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Undated, excerpt from undetermined letter (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Murray
    - 3/9/29, Don Tresidder to Mrs. Herbert Hoover (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1932, from student of Dr. Murray to his parents (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Writings
  - Biography (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Information for National Cyclopedia of American Biography (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Excerpt Pan-Pacific Who's Who (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Tribute--March 11, 1940--Memorial Church, Dr. D. C. Gardner (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Resolution--Academic Council, Stanford University, April 5, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Paper--conferring degree of Doctor of Laws (Haverford College) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Excerpt--Irish Monthly, January 1915, concerning Murray's translation of the Odyssey (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Excerpt from "Autobiography" by John Cowper Powys, 1934, concerning Murray's translation of the Illiad and the Odyssey (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Notebook--notes on classical works and other literary works (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Notebook--lectures on the Psalms (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Notebook--notes on Whittier; genealogy included in back of notebook (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Religious Writings
    - "An Adventure in Unity" (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - The Friends Meeting of Washington, D.C. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Some Thoughts on Worship (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Quakerism and the Present Crisis (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - The Faith of Man. I, II, III (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Worship (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - What I Believe and Why (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Untitled (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Sermons
    - Thanksgiving, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - December 4, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Christmas, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - January 8, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - January 15, 1939 (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - January 22, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - January 28, 1939 (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - February 5, 1939 (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - February 12, 1939 (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - February 25, 1939 (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Religious Notes and Presentations (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Religious Notes--miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Notebook--religion (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Additional papers, Accession ARCH-2017-238
  Scope and Contents
  Collage/Cartoons.
  - "Bringing Up Father/Somewhere in Yosemite" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Father" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Sister" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Usual Time and Place" (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Usual Time & Place" (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Bay" (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Mother" (Box 1, Folder 6)